<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code on Vicky&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code on Vicky&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you likes to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 21:47:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Deep Neural Network in R</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/neural-network/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had an interview for a data science job and I was asked to explain a neural network (which I responded with a quite hand-wavy answer). I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while so thought this would be a good to show a simple deep neural network in R that I did a while back. The code below implements a DNN in R (of one hidden layer, with Rectified Linear Unit, L2 regularisation and Softmax loss function).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make an automatic back-up server using an old raspberry pi</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/raspberry-pi-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/raspberry-pi-backup/</guid>
      <description>This is a nice and easy project if you need to back up lots of data automatically from your workspace - in my case genomic data from an HPC cluster I wanted to back-up locally in case of disaster. I had an old raspberry pi lying around and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put it to good use. The benefits of using a raspberry pi instead of a laptop or PC is you can just leave your raspberry pi on and let it do its thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Linux</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/install-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/install-linux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the time to install Linux! (I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed it&amp;rsquo;s taken this long.)
Installing Ubuntu Alongside Windows 8.1 I used this fantastic installation guide, courtesy of Gary Newell, plus a few tricks of the trade specific to my battered (but well-loved) Acer Aspire laptop.
Installing any operating system boils down to these basic steps (which is explained in detail in the tutorial):
Back-up or be sorry&amp;hellip; I created a Disk Image of Windows 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/hidden-markov-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/index/post/code/hidden-markov-models/</guid>
      <description>Hidden Markov models here, there and everywhere! Here’s a short and sweet description of a Hidden Markov model used to generate a short DNA sequence, and accompanying R code.
Brief rundown of the Hidden Markov Model (HMM) The nucleotides are basically the letters that make up a DNA sequence: “A”, “T”, “G” and “C”. In a sequence generated by the Markov Model, the probability of finding a nucleotide (or letter) at a particular position in a sequence depends on the nucleotide found at the previous position.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>