<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vicky&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vicky&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you likes to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities for women in STEM</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/women-in-stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/women-in-stem/</guid>
      <description> Learn to code with these friendly communities:  Hear from women in computing @ researc/hers code (beginners to advanced) Learn R @ R-Ladies London (beginners to advanced) Machine Learning @ The AI CLub (intermediate to advanced) Create websites @ Code First: Girls (beginners) Data science @ Inspiring Women in Data Science (beginners) Data science @ Women in Kaggle (intermediate to advanced)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Current PhD Computational biology and microbiology at the Centre for Host-Microbiome Interactions at King&amp;rsquo;s College London
President of Innovation Forum, King&amp;rsquo;s College London Branch Learn more about Innovation Forum and check out the London Branch activities:
 Event Highlights: Looking into the Future of Science Innovation She Started It: Top Tips for Women in STEM Advancing Innovation in Healthcare at King&amp;rsquo;s College London A View into the Innovations Towards a Sustainable Future Bio-engineering of the future: a peek at &amp;ldquo;Innovation in Synthetic Biology&amp;rdquo;  Organiser of the Women in Computing Seminar Series Check out the meetup group, recent seminar and apply to be a speaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Deep Neural Network in R</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/neural-network/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had an interview for a data science job and I was asked to explain a neural network (which I responded with a quite hand-wavy answer). I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while so thought this would be a good to show a simple deep neural network in R that I did a while back. The code below implements a DNN in R (of one hidden layer, with Rectified Linear Unit, L2 regularisation and Softmax loss function).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make an automatic back-up server using an old raspberry pi</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/raspberry-pi-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/raspberry-pi-backup/</guid>
      <description>This is a nice and easy project if you need to back up lots of data automatically from your workspace - in my case genomic data from an HPC cluster I wanted to back-up locally in case of disaster. I had an old raspberry pi lying around and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put it to good use. The benefits of using a raspberry pi instead of a laptop or PC is you can just leave your raspberry pi on and let it do its thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in Computing Seminar Series</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/women-in-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/women-in-computing/</guid>
      <description>On 13th July, Dr Simone Ecker, Research Associate from the UCL Cancer Institute presented her research for the Women in Computing Seminar Series. Simone talked about epigenetics and how she uses bioinformatics to answer questions on DNA methylation and gene expression variability in human blood cells.
It was a full-house and Simone&amp;rsquo;s talk was well-received, generating lots of discussion about how variability is overlooked across many disciplines of statistics.
To read about her research, check out UCL&amp;rsquo;s recent news story on her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is my PhD?</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/phd/</guid>
      <description>Realised I haven&amp;rsquo;t said much on the PhD front. Rotations are now over, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently drafting the PhD project. What I can be sure of is it contains many &amp;lsquo;omes&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;
Here&amp;rsquo;s a sneak peak at what I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at:
1) Analysis of metagenomic data of microbes in the oral cavity. Basically all the microbes&amp;rsquo; DNA in a mouth..
2) Mobilome (funnier said aloud). Lots of mobile genetic elements, the genes that move across microbes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Linux</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/install-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/install-linux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the time to install Linux! (I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed it&amp;rsquo;s taken this long.)
Installing Ubuntu Alongside Windows 8.1 I used this fantastic installation guide, courtesy of Gary Newell, plus a few tricks of the trade specific to my battered (but well-loved) Acer Aspire laptop.
Installing any operating system boils down to these basic steps (which is explained in detail in the tutorial):
Back-up or be sorry&amp;hellip; I created a Disk Image of Windows 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/hidden-markov-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/hidden-markov-models/</guid>
      <description>Hidden Markov models here, there and everywhere! Here’s a short and sweet description of a Hidden Markov model used to generate a short DNA sequence, and accompanying R code.
Brief rundown of the Hidden Markov Model (HMM) The nucleotides are basically the letters that make up a DNA sequence: “A”, “T”, “G” and “C”. In a sequence generated by the Markov Model, the probability of finding a nucleotide (or letter) at a particular position in a sequence depends on the nucleotide found at the previous position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Researchers &amp; Students Community Launch</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/rladies-research-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/rladies-research-launch/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I gave a bioinformatics talk and workshop for the launch event of R-Ladies London&amp;rsquo;s new Researchers and Students Community. R-Ladies is a world-wide organisation to promote gender diversity in the R community. The R-Ladies London branch has been running for just over a year, and have been providing workshops (in R, Github) for beginners to advanced level.
The R-Ladies community and attendees of these events are mainly gender minorities from research and academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blue-moon22.github.io/blog/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello, world! Welcome to my new blog. I will be writing about:
 some of the cool research I&amp;rsquo;m doing pickings of bioinformatics and programming outreach events that I will be doing  Watch this space&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>